All right now let's actually look at a compromise situation where two people disagree about the price
好吧，现在让我们实际看看两个人在价格上存在分歧的折衷情况
of a car.
一辆车。
We've done this a little bit before when we were talking about the apartment.
我们之前在谈论公寓时已经这样做了。
But I want to make sure we look at the situation with some of the phrases that we've talked about so
但我想确保我们用我们讨论过的一些短语来看待这种情况
far.
远的。
OK.
好的。
So on the Web site this is the buyer the person who might buy the car.
所以在网站上，这是可能购买汽车的买家。
And this is the this is the seller.
这就是这就是卖方。
This is the seller.
这是卖家。
OK here we go on the website.
好的，我们进入网站。
The car is listed for five thousand eight hundred.
该车标价五千八百。
That means that's the price that it says on the Web site.
这意味着这就是它在网站上所说的价格。
But I think that's a little steep.
但我认为这有点陡峭。
That's a little steep.
这有点陡峭。
By the way we could say here.
顺便说一句，我们可以在这里说。
Fifty eight hundred.
五千八百。
Sometimes people say fifty eight hundred fifty eight hundred dollars but five thousand eight hundred
有时人们说五千八百五千八百美元，但五千八百
dollars is more common.
美元更常见。
Steep means too expensive given how many miles are on it.
考虑到它有多少英里，陡峭意味着太贵了。
I think five thousand two hundred dollars would be fair.
我认为五千二百美元是公平的。
So this is the offer.
所以这就是报价。
OK.
好的。
This is the offer the low offer.
这是报价的低报价。
I just don't see it that way.
我只是不这么看。
We could say I don't quite see it that way.
我们可以说我不这么看。
We don't have to say it like that.
我们不必那样说。
As I said the car has been kept in excellent condition.
正如我所说，这辆车一直保持良好状态。
In fact I think this car could go for six thousand dollars.
事实上，我认为这辆车可以卖到六千美元。
Go for means.
寻求手段。
That's the price that some people might be willing to pay.
这是一些人可能愿意付出的代价。
Sometimes we use go for when we're talking about the amount that you could sell something a little more
有时，当我们谈论您可以多卖一些东西的数量时，我们会使用 go for
expensive for.
昂贵的。
We don't usually use it for small things like candy or bottles of water but for things like houses and
我们通常不会将它用于糖果或瓶装水之类的小东西，而是用于房屋和
cars and sometimes clothes sometimes we can use go for I can't believe that these go for fifty eight
汽车，有时是衣服，有时我们可以用去，我不敢相信这些去五十八
dollars.
美元。
These shoes go for fifty eight dollars.
这双鞋要五十八美元。
It's so expensive.
它太贵了。
OK go for.
好的去吧。
All right.
好的。
Let's go to the next part of this negotiation.
让我们进入谈判的下一部分。
So far we've used this phrase.
到目前为止，我们已经使用了这个短语。
I just don't see it that way.
我只是不这么看。
OK.
好的。
Then the buyer says it's just so far out of my price range too expensive so far out of my price range.
然后买家说它离我的价格范围太远了，太贵了，超出了我的价格范围。
Would you be willing to consider five thousand three hundred dollars.
你愿意考虑五千三百美元。
Would you be willing to consider.
是否愿意考虑。
So it's another offer.
所以这是另一个提议。
One hundred dollars more.
一百多块钱。
There's another phrase.
还有一句话。
I'll tell you what this is when the seller is going to show that he or she is ready to compromise.
当卖方要表明他或她准备妥协时，我会告诉你这是什么情况。
I'll tell you what means I'm going to give you a better deal now if you can pay in cash.
我会告诉你，如果你能用现金支付，我现在会给你一个更好的交易意味着什么。
I could do five thousand six hundred do that if you can do something.
如果你能做点什么，我可以做五千六百件事。
It's like saying that works for me.
这就像说这对我有用。
Hey I want to meet around 4 o'clock.
嘿，我想在 4 点左右见面。
Does that work for you.
那对你有用吗。
Yeah.
是的。
That works for me.
这对我行得通。
Or you can say Yeah I can do for.
或者你可以说是的，我可以做到。
I can do for.
我可以为。
That's fine.
没关系。
I can do that.
我能做到。
I could do five thousand six hundred dollars.
我可以赚五千六百美元。
I can pay cash fine if you can meet me in the middle on the price.
如果你能在价格上与我见面，我可以支付现金罚款。
Meet me in the middle on the price.
在价格中间见我。
So two people on two ends.
所以两个人在两端。
Five thousand four hundred five thousand four hundred.
五千四十五万四百。
That would be about the middle.
那将是大约中间。
Right.
正确的。
Meet me in the middle on the price then maybe the seller will say Oh OK OK you've got a deal.
在价格中间见我，然后卖家可能会说哦，好的，你有交易。
You got a deal.
你达成了协议。
You've got yourself a deal sometimes.
有时你会得到一笔交易。
So we've used some of the phrases for how we can negotiate and more importantly compromise when we're
因此，我们使用了一些短语来说明我们如何进行谈判，更重要的是，当我们
ready to give up something.
准备放弃一些东西。
It's very important in many conversations you have this opinion they have this opinion it's necessary
在许多对话中非常重要，你有这个观点他们有这个观点这是必要的
to sometimes give up a few of your ideas.
有时会放弃你的一些想法。
A few of the things you want in order to make other people happy and come to a solution to your problems.
你想要的一些事情是为了让其他人开心并解决你的问题。
All right.
好的。
We're going to go on and talk about some difficulty and how we can describe some difficulties.
我们将继续讨论一些困难以及我们如何描述一些困难。